

# CONTACT

**(**, 650.575.4651

✓ filatovaa@yahoo.com

anna-filatova.com

github.com/1anya1

(in) inkedin.com/in/anna-filatova

# **SKILLS**

#### > Frontend:

Javascript

HTML5

CSS3

React

Bootstrap

Sass

jQuery

ES6

Animations

# > Backend:

Ruby on Rails

Node.js

Express.js

MongoDB

Mongoose

JWT

**JSON** 

NoSQL

PostgreSQL

## > Other:

Git

Agile Development Data Structures MERN stack

Database Modeling

## **PROJECTS**

Please visit my website to see the latest projects that I've been working on.

# **Anna** Filatova

# **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

#### **ABOUT**

I am a passionate creator of things on the web who enjoys all forms of design. I love to plan my ideas thoughtfully, then craft them into creative, yet user-friendly experiences. My technical background includes the latest development approaches in programming, including MVC framework, event-driven applications using AJAX, JSON, and Object-Oriented JavaScript. I am an agile learner who enjoys problem-solving and picking up new skills and tools.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Promotely**

2020 - now

Frontend Developer

San Francisco, CA

- Developed web applications using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, and JavaScript
- ▶ Implemented responsive web design to ensure website crossbrowser compatibility and mobile responsiveness
- ▶ Programmed various AJAX and JSON calls for the communication between the server and the UI
- ▶ Developed a flexible and well-structured front-end architecture, along with the APIs to support it
- ▶ Built the Single Page Application (SPA) with React Router

#### **General Assembly**

2019 - 2020

Software Engineer Fellow

San Francisco, CA

- ► Architected RESTful APIs with Node.js, Express, and Mongoose to complete CRUD operations in backend
- Achieved user authentication and authorization using JSON Web Tokens
- Used AJAX to make asynchronous calls to the project server to fetch data
- ▶ Deployed both client-side and server-side to Heroku and cPanel
- ▶ Tested sites in various browsers and devices for cross-platform optimization

## Yelp

2017-2019

Account Executive

San Francisco, CA

- ▶ Managed pipeline of 2000+ businesses
- ▶ Hit and exceed monthly sales goals, promoted three times in 19 months
- ▶ Drove the full sale cycle to attain new business: vetted prospects, assessed business goals through qualifying, closed deals

#### **EDUCATION**

# General Assembly - 2020

Penn State University - 2016

Software Engineering Immersive

Bachelor of Arts in Economics